Finding Aid for the Edward C. Weber Papers, 1949-2005
Edward C. Weber Papers
University of Michigan Library (Special Collections Research Center)
Edward C. Weber Papers 1949-2006
Weber, Edward Charles, 1922-
28.0 Linear feet (54 manuscript boxes, 1 oversized box.)
Printed material in boxes 1-54. Photographic material occasionally attached to correspondence in boxes 1-54. Box 55 contains two oversized items, each framed in wood.
weber
Edward C. Weber (1922-2006) was long-time curator of the University of Michigan Special Collection’s Joseph A. Labadie Collection of radical history. Under his stewardship, the Labadie Collection grew into one of the premier and most forward-thinking holdings of materials relating to radical and protest groups from the United States and around the world. The Edward C. Weber Papers are made up of the subject’s correspondence and biographical materials, written from 1949 to 2006. The bulk of the collection, the correspondence is mostly comprised of Weber’s letters soliciting materials on behalf of the Labadie Collection or fielding reference questions from researchers, as well as personal correspondence from the his family and friends. The collection’s materials are comprised of letters (typed and handwritten), printed out emails, postcards, greeting cards, news clippings, photographs, printed biographical materials, framed commendations, and other miscellaneous paper materials.
University of Michigan Library (Special Collections Research Center) Joseph A. Labadie Collection
Immediate Source of Acquisition Note
Acquired from Edward Weber and his associates. In addition, folders containing Weber’s solicitations on behalf of the Special Collections were taken directly from the Joseph A. Labadie Collection in 2008.
Conditions Governing Access Note
The collection is open for research.
Longtime curator of the Joseph A. Labadie Collection within the University of Michigan’s Special Collections, Edward C. Weber (1922-2006) was a critical figure within the University’s library system and an active supporter of various marginalized communities.
Born September 14, 1922 in Rochester, NY, he earned an undergraduate degree from the University of Rochester followed by a master’s degree in American literature from Columbia University. He made his way to the Ann Arbor area to attend the University of Michigan’s library school in 1952. While a student, he began working part-time as a reference librarian at the university’s Social Science Library. He continued working within the library system after completing his education and became head of the Labadie Collection in 1960 (Daub, 2006).
A prominent resource within the University of Michigan’s Special Collections, the Labadie Collection is the oldest publicly-accessible collection for radical history, containing items from a diverse array of social protest and radical movements that date from the nineteenth to twenty-first centuries. Under Weber’s guidance and persistent outreach, the Labadie Collection developed rich holdings for the Sixtie’s anti-war, modern anarchism, gay liberation, radical feminism, pacifism, and ecology movements. By actively providing representation to these marginalized communities within the library’s holdings, the Labadie Collection was for a period one of the few significant scholarly resources for gay, feminist, and anti-war studies. By the time Weber retired in 2000, the Labadie Collection had grown six-fold and was firmly entrenched as a primary resource for scholarship of the history of radicalism ("History").
Besides managing the Labadie Collection, Weber was critical for developing collections regarding Latin American studies, theater, and minority literature for the university’s library system (Daub, 2006). In addition to his work within the library, Weber was a proud member of the local Ann Arbor community, participating as manager of the Cinema Guild for 37 years and actively supporting the University Musical Society (Retzloff, 2006).
Edward Weber passed away at the age of 83 on April 11, 2006.
References:
“History”. MLibrary. http://www.lib.umich.edu/labadie-collection/history [Accessed 3/21/2013]
“Joseph Labadie Anarchy Collection. (December 24, 1998). C-SPAN School Bus. http://www.c-spanvideo.org/program/117475-1 [Accessed 3/21/2013]
Retzloff, Tim. (April 20, 2006). “Edward Weber, retired Labadie Collection curator at U of M, dies at 83”. Pride Source: Between the Lines News. http://www.pridesource.com/article.html?article=18419 [Accessed 3/21/2013]
The Edward C. Weber Papers consists of Weber’s correspondence with organizations, publishers, researchers, associates, family, and friends, along with biographical materials created for his retirement and memorial services. The collection provides a snapshot of the Joseph A. Labadie Collection and his work there for a 40 year period (1960-2000), as well as a portrait of his personal relationships with friends and family from 1949 to 2005.
The Biographical Materials series contains materials from Weber’s retirement celebration and memorial service. The first folder contains past articles and correspondence on paper stock, reprinted for Weber’s memorial service in 2006. The second set of items relate to Weber’s retirement in 2000. This includes a flyer for his retirement celebration, articles about his retirement, and copied certificates of commendation. In addition, two framed items of commendation are housed in an oversized box.
The Correspondence series makes up the majority of the collection and is comprised of 27 linear feet of paper material housed in 54 manuscript boxes, foldered alphabetically by correspondent or corresponding organization. Individual letters, cards, photographs and other types of written communication are arranged chronologically within each subject’s folder(s). The majority of folders are dedicated to outreach by Weber to various radical groups and individuals soliciting material donations to contribute to the Labadie Collection. His written responses to reference inquiries for items within the Labadie Collection make up another significant segment of the series. Most of these materials are typewritten letters officially sent on behalf of the Labadie Collection and University of Michigan Special Collections. Some later letters were written by Labadie Collection assistants during Weber’s time there and with his knowledge. Since Weber never used email, his letters sent on behalf of the Labadie Collection were typed on a manual or electric typewriter. There are occasional handwritten notations on some of these letters and a few emails printed out so he could read them. Other folders in the series contain personal correspondence from friends, family, and other associates. These items are made up mostly of handwritten notes, postcards, greeting cards, newspaper clippings, printouts of emails, occasional photographs, and other miscellaneous items. Many of the folders were removed from the general Labadie correspondence files in 2008 and a listing was made of them at that time. The rest of the series is made up of personal correspondence Weber stored in his home.
Within the series are several notable, lengthy correspondence partners including Theodore Adams (1950-2004, 21 folders), James Q. Belden (1952-2000, 11 folders), George Nick (1949-1991, 12 folders), Curtis and Clarice Rodgers (1961-2005, 18 folders), and Henry Van Dyke (1950-2004, 12 folders). The series also includes correspondence from notable individuals such as civil rights activist Malcolm X, graphic novelist Harvey Pekar, former Secretary of State Eliot Abrams, the White Panther Party, among many others.
Abbreviations:
LC=Labadie Collection ECW=Edward C. Weber
Subjects:
Labadie Collection (Harlan Hatcher Graduate Library); Librarians -- Ann Arbor (Mich.); Radicalism -- Library resources; Radicalism--United States--History
Genre Terms:
Correspondence.
- Biographical Materials
  - Memorial Items (2006) (Box 1)
  - Retirement party materials (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - A is A (Box 1)
  - A Batalha (Box 1)
  - AKA Books (Box 1)
  - AAH Examiner (Box 1)
  - AMPO (Tokyo, Japan) (Box 1)
  - AMS Press Film Service (Box 1)
  - A.C.E.P.P.O.S. (Association pour la Conservation Etude de la Presse Ouvriere et Syndicate) (Box 1)
  - AFL-CIO Library (Box 1)
  - AFL-CIO News (Washington DC) (Box 1)
  - ALF Support Group (Toronto) (Box 1)
  - AMS Press Film Service (Box 1)
  - ABAS (Newark, NJ) (Box 1)
  - Abcarian, Gilbert (Box 1)
  - Abels, Kurt (reference: Karl Heinzen) (Box 1)
  - Abolitionist/Outlook (Newark, NJ) (Box 1)
  - About Face (New York, NY) (Box 1)
  - Abrams, Elliott (U.S. Secretary of State) (Box 1)
  - Abrams, Irving S. (Pioneer Aid and Support Association) (Box 1)
  - Accion Libertaria (Argentina) (Box 1)
  - Accuracy in Academia (Box 1)
  - Achebe Enterprises (Box 1)
  - Acorn (Box 1)
  - Action (New York) (Box 1)
  - L’Action Europeene (Paris) (Box 1)
  - Activist (Buffalo) (Box 1)
  - Activist, The (Oberlin) (Box 1)
  - Adamic Knights of the Ku Klux Klan (Box 1)
  - Adams, Graham, Jr.(reference: Paterson Strike, 1913) (Box 1)
  - Adams, Dr. Paul L. (Box 1)
  - Adams, Theodore S. (8 of 21 folders) (Box 1)
  - Adams, Theodore S. (10 of 21 folders) (Box 2)
  - Adams, Theodore S. (3 of 21 folders) (Box 3)
  - Adel, Hilda (Box 3)
  - Adkins, Charles (reference: Spanish Socialist Workers Party) (Box 3)
  - Adler, Joseph (Box 3)
  - Adler, Joyce Sparer (Box 3)
  - Advocate (Los Angeles) (Box 3)
  - Advocators (Detroit) (Box 3)
  - Aegis (Washington DC) (Box 3)
  - Africa and the World (London) (Box 3)
  - Africa Bureau, The (Box 3)
  - Africa Publications Trust (Box 3)
  - Africa Research Group (Box 3)
  - African Agenda (Chicago) (Box 3)
  - African Americans for Humanism (Box 3)
  - African Communist, The (London) (Box 3)
  - African National Congress/Sechaba Publications (Box 3)
  - Afro-American Magazine (New York) (Box 3)
  - Afro-American Museum of Detroit (Box 3)
  - Afros Expressions (Waukegan, Ill.) (Box 3)
  - After Stonewall (Winnipeg, Manitoba) (Box 3)
  - Against the Wall (Westfield, NJ) (Box 3)
  - Agel, Jerome B. (reference: I.W.W) (Box 3)
  - Agitazione del Sud (Palermo, Italy) (Box 3)
  - Agora (Toulouse, France) (Box 3)
  - Aimer, Ron G. (reference: Red Scare in Detroit) (Box 3)
  - Ain’t I A Woman (Iowa City) (Box 3)
  - Ajoblanco (Barcelona) (Box 3)
  - Akbar, Na’im (Box 3)
  - Akwesasne Notes (Rooseveltown, NY) (Box 3)
  - Albania Report (New York) (Box 3)
  - Albany Trust – Man and Society (London) (Box 3)
  - Albatross (East Orange, NJ) (Box 3)
  - Albro, Ward S. (reference: Ricardo Flores Magon) (Box 3)
  - Aleksandrov, Grigori (Moscow) (Box 3)
  - Alianza Federal de Pueblos Libres (Box 3)
  - Alive and Trucking Theater (Box 3)
  - Alive Magazine (Ontario, Canada) (Box 3)
  - Alland, Alexander Jr. (Box 3)
  - All Points of View (San Antonio, TX) (Box 3)
  - Allen, Bruce (reference: Carl Harp, North American Anarchist, Strike!) (Box 3)
  - Allen, Ernest Jr. (reference: Moslem Sunrise) (Box 3)
  - Allen, Julia M. (reference: Grace Hutchins, Anna Rochester) (Box 3)
  - Alternate Society (Ontario, Canada) (Box 3)
  - Alternative Rides Again (New York) (Box 3)
  - Alternative Press Index (Centre) (Box 3)
  - Alternate Publishing (Box 3)
  - Alternatives Foundation (Modern Utopian, Visions) (Box 3)
  - Altherr, Marco (reference: First International) (Box 3)
  - Amazon Quarterly (Oakland, CA) (Box 3)
  - American Antiquarian Society (Box 3)
  - American Arts Documentation Centre, U. of Exeter, England (Box 3)
  - American Atheists, Inc. (Box 3)
  - American Book Publishers Council, Inc. (Box 3)
  - American-Chilean Council (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union of New Jersey (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union of Northern California (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union of Southern California (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (Washington, D.C.) (Box 3)
  - American Committee on Africa (Box 3)
  - American Dialog (New York) (Box 3)
  - American Federationist (Washington DC) (Box 4)
  - American Flag Committee Newsletter (Philadelphia) (Box 4)
  - American Friends Service Committee (Box 4)
  - American Heritage Magazine (reference: IWW) (Box 4)
  - American Institute for Marxist Studies (Box 4)
  - American Nazi Party (Box 4)
  - American Nonconformist (Winfield, KS) (Box 4)
  - American Opinion (Belmont, MA) (Box 4)
  - American Report (New York) (Box 4)
  - American Splendor (contains postcard from Harvey Pekar (Box 4)
  - Americans for Democratic Action (Leon Shull) (Box 4)
  - America’s Future (Box 4)
  - AMEX-Canada (Toronto) (Box 4)
  - Les Amis de Panait Istrati ( Cahiers) (Box 4)
  - Amnesty International (Box 4)
  - Among Friends (New York) (Box 4)
  - Ammunition (UAW) (Detroit) (Box 4)
  - An Phoblacht (Ireland) (Box 4)
  - Anamika (New York) (Box 4)
  - L’anarchie (Raymond Beaulation) (France) (Box 4)
  - Anarchism et non-violence (France) (Box 4)
  - Anarchismo (Italy) (Box 4)
  - Anarchist, The (Australia) (Box 4)
  - Anarchist Alliance of Aotearoa ( The State Adversary) (New Zealand) (Box 4)
  - Anarchist Black Dragon (Montrèal) (Box 4)
  - Anarchist Feminist Notes (Jamaica Plain) (Box 4)
  - Anarchist Federation of Britain (Box 4)
  - Anarchist Group, The (Box 4)
  - Anarchives (France) (Box 4)
  - L’Anarcho-Syndicaliste (France) (Box 4)
  - Anarchos (Greece) (Box 4)
  - Anarchos (New York) (Box 4)
  - Anarchy Magazine (London) (also contains info on Russian anarchists during revolution) (Box 4)
  - Anderson, Olive M. (reference: Hiawatha Village Association) (Box 4)
  - Andréas, Bert (reference: Karl Heinzen, German radicals, IWMA) (Box 4)
  - Animal Liberation Front Support Group (Canada) (Box 4)
  - Ann Arbor Argus (Box 4)
  - Ann Arbor District Library (Box 4)
  - Ann Arbor Metro Times (Box 4)
  - Ann Arbor Tenants Union (Box 4)
  - Annunziata, Frank (reference: general inquiry) (Box 4)
  - Anthony, Elizabeth A. (Box 4)
  - Anti-Apartheid Movement (Box 4)
  - Anti-Apartheid News (London) (Box 4)
  - Anti-Castration League (Box 4)
  - Antipode (Mass.) (Box 4)
  - Antorcha (Mexico) (Enrique Flores Magon) (Box 4)
  - ApaEros (Corvallis, OR) (Box 4)
  - Apfelbaum, Charles (Box 4)
  - Aphra (New York) (Box 4)
  - Appeal to Reason (Chicago) (Box 4)
  - Appeal to Reason (Thousand Oaks, CA) (Box 4)
  - Appalachian Movement Press (Box 4)
  - Aranoff, S. (Box 4)
  - Arbetaren (Sweden) (Box 4)
  - Archer, Dane (Box 4)
  - Archief en Museum van de Socialistische Arbeidersbeweging (Box 4)
  - Archives Project, The (Box 4)
  - Arcos, Federico (Box 4)
  - Arena Three (London) (superseded by Gay Girl) (Box 4)
  - Arguimbau, Ellen H. (reference: Colorado Coal Miners Strike 1901) (Box 4)
  - Arnold, Ronnie (reference: Ross Barnett) (Box 4)
  - Aronson, Ronald (Box 4)
  - Aronson, Stacey L Parker (reference: Spanish Civil War poetry) (Box 4)
  - Arthur Morgan School (Box 4)
  - Arvind, Savir (Trikon) (Box 4)
  - Ashbaugh, Carolyn (Lucy Parsons) (Box 4)
  - Askatasuna (Spain) (Box 4)
  - Assembly of Captive European Nations (Box 4)
  - Asociacion Isaac Puente: Centro de Documentación Estudios Anarquistas (Spain) (Box 4)
  - Association for the Study of Negro Life and History (Box 4)
  - Association for Union Democracy (Box 4)
  - Association Max Sterner du Kébec ( La Feuille) (Montréal) (Box 4)
  - Association of Eritrean Students in North America (Box 4)
  - Association of Libertarian Feminists (Box 4)
  - Astral Projection (New Mexico) (Box 4)
  - Ater, P. J. ( Lookout) (Seattle) (Box 4)
  - Atlanta Inquirer (Box 4)
  - Atlantis News (Saugerties, NY) (Box 4)
  - Atobá (Brazil) (Box 4)
  - Attack (Wash. DC) (National Youth Alliance) (Box 4)
  - Attica Brigade (Fight Back!) (New York) (Box 4)
  - Aube, Edwin L. (reference: United Steel Workers) (Box 4)
  - Auderson, Charlotta (Box 5)
  - Auerbach, Jerold S. (reference: La Follette Civil Liberties Committee) (Box 5)
  - Augur, The (Eugene, OR) (Box 5)
  - Augusta Courier (Box 5)
  - Avakumovic, Ivan (reference: anarchism) (Box 5)
  - Avatar (Boston) (Box 5)
  - Ayer, Hugh M. (reference: Labor, Indiana, 1940s) (Box 5)
  - Ayers, Rick (Box 5)
  - Ayn Rand Letter (New York) (Box 5)
  - Azania News (Tanzania) (Box 5)
  - Azione Diretta (Switzerland) (Box 5)
  - Azione Nonviolenta (Italy) (Box 5)
  - BB Books (Box 5)
  - B.C. Blackout (British Columbia) (Box 5)
  - BLK (Los Angeles) (Box 5)
  - Babilonia (Italy) (Box 5)
  - Babylon Press (Box 5)
  - Backall, Morris (reference: Haymarket) (Box 5)
  - Bacon, Gordon T. (Box 5)
  - Bad Haircut (Olympia, WA) (Box 5)
  - BAD Press (Cambridge, MA) (Box 5)
  - Bagnall, Carlene (Box 5)
  - Bailey, Richard and Carol (Box 5)
  - Bailey, Hubert (Box 5)
  - Baker, Deane (Box 5)
  - Bales, James D. (reference: communism, Inprecor) (Box 5)
  - Balis, Samuel (reference: Nicolai V. Chaikovski) (Box 5)
  - Ballantine, Betty (Box 5)
  - Ballantine, David (Ian) (Box 5)
  - Balliot, Bob (reference: Bill Hawywood murder trial) (Box 5)
  - Balzer, Anitra (reference: Schmidt-Caplan case 1910) (Box 5)
  - Bandiera Rossa (Italy) (Box 5)
  - Bandwagon (South Africa) (Box 5)
  - Bar None (Somerville, MA) (Box 5)
  - Barb, The (Atlanta) (Box 5)
  - Barisonzi, Jeannette (reference: Lucy Parsons, Jo Labadie, Emma Goldman’s literary heirs) (Box 5)
  - Baskin, Alex (reference: death masks of Sacco and Vanzetti, Bingo, Ralph Chaplin, Art Young, etc.) (Box 5)
  - Barkun, Michael (reference: Coxey’s Army) (Box 5)
  - Barlow, Jennifer (Box 5)
  - Basen, Neil (reference: Kate Richards O’Hare, National Socialist, Caroline A. Lowe (Box 5)
  - Bart, Philip (reference: Blacks in the left-wing trade union movement) (Box 5)
  - Bartoletti, Efrem (from William Morgan, Curator of the Labadie Collection) (Box 5)
  - Basic Pamphlets (Box 5)
  - Bassett, Dr. David (Box 5)
  - Bates, Scott (reference: homosexuality of Jesus) (Box 5)
  - Batterham, David (bookseller) (Box 5)
  - Battler (Australia) (Box 5)
  - Battye, John H. (reference: Richard Trevellick) (Box 5)
  - Bauls of the Brickyard (Indiana) (Box 5)
  - Baum, Janet (Box 5)
  - Baxandall, Lee (reference: Harriet Orcutt, May Beals, Lois Waisbrooker, socialist culture in the U.S.) (Box 5)
  - Baxandall, Rosalyn (reference: Elizabeth Gurley Flynn) (Box 5)
  - Bay Area Students Committee (Box 5)
  - Bay Area Reporter ( Bay Times) (Box 5)
  - Bay Area Worker (San Francisco) (Box 5)
  - Beals, Carleton (reference: Jack Johnson) (Box 5)
  - Beam, Dorothy (re: Joseph Beam) (Box 5)
  - Beam, Joe (reference: Blacklight) (Box 5)
  - Beck, Bruce (Box 5)
  - Becker, Heiner (Box 5)
  - Beffel, John Nicholas (re: Covington Hall manuscript, obituaries, IWW) (Box 5)
  - Befreiung (Colon, Germany) (Box 5)
  - Belden, James Q. (11 of 11 folders) (Box 6)
  - Bell, The (Birmingham, England) (Box 7)
  - Bell and Howell (Micro Photo Division) (Box 7)
  - Bellamy, Joyce M. (reference: John Francis Bray) (Box 7)
  - Bendler, Mary K. (Box 7)
  - Benedict, Russell G. (Univ. of Nevada; Collectors of Nuttiness/CON) (Box 7)
  - Benito, Aldrich (Box 7)
  - Benjamins, John (Antiquariat) (Box 7)
  - Benjelloun, Abdelmajid (reference: 1936 revolt against Franco in northern Morocco) (Box 7)
  - Bennett, Blythe Allison (reference: songs and posters of the Spanish Civil War) (Box 7)
  - Benni (Box 7)
  - Bentley Historical Collections (see also Michigan Historical Collections) (Box 7)
  - Bentley, Wilder (Box 7)
  - Berbier, Mitch (reference: LGBT, white supremacists as minorities) (Box 7)
  - Berch, Victor A. (Brandeis Univ. – Spanish Civil War materials) (Box 7)
  - Le Berdache (Montrèal) (Box 7)
  - Berg, Margaret (Box 7)
  - Bergin, Barry (Box 7)
  - Berkeley Barb (Box 7)
  - Sanford Berman (Box 7)
  - Berndt, Louise (Box 7)
  - Bernecker, Walther (reference: Spanish Civil War) (Box 7)
  - Bernstein, Anna J. (Box 7)
  - Bernstein, Dennis (Box 7)
  - Berry, Mrs. Elizabeth (reference: Emma Goldman) (Box 7)
  - Bertrand Russell Archives (Box 7)
  - Bertrand Russell Peace Foundation (Box 7)
  - Bers, Gunter (reference: Wilhelm Hasselmann) (Box 7)
  - Bersin, Mollie Klapper (reference: Sunrise Cooperative Farm Community) (Box 7)
  - Bessie, Dan (Box 7)
  - Beth Hatefutsoth-Museum of the Jewish Diaspora (Box 7)
  - Between the Lines (Detroit, MI) (Box 7)
  - Between the Lines (Newtown, PA) (Box 7)
  - Betzold, Michael (re: Sunrise Cooperative Farm Community) (Box 7)
  - Beyond Baroque (Venice, CA) (Box 7)
  - Biafra (Lisbon, Portugal) (Box 7)
  - Biehl, Janet (Box 7)
  - Bilalian News (ECW letter to the Editor) (Box 7)
  - Bingham, Emily (reference: Max Edgeworth Lazarus) (Box 7)
  - Binkley, Dave (reference: The Emancipator) (Box 7)
  - Bi-Plane (New York) (Box 7)
  - Birmingham GLF ( Gladrag - England) (Box 7)
  - Birth Press (Tuli Kupferberg) (Box 7)
  - Birula, Katherine (reference: William Walker Atkinson) (Box 7)
  - Bit (London) (Box 7)
  - Bittelman, Alex (Box 7)
  - Bjerke, John A. (reference: IWW in Oregon, Justice) (Box 7)
  - Black and Red (Detroit) (Box 7)
  - Black and Red (Manchester, England) (Box 7)
  - Black and White Men Together (Chicago) (Box 7)
  - Black and White Men Together (San Diego) (Box 7)
  - Black and White Men Together (San Francisco) (Box 7)
  - Black Bart Brigade (Canyon, CA) (Box 7)
  - Black Cat Press (Alberta, Canada) (Box 7)
  - Black Collegian (New Orleans) (Box 7)
  - Black Dialogue (New York) (Box 7)
  - Black Dwarf (London) (Box 7)
  - Black Flag (London) (Box 7)
  - Black, Henry T. (Book dealer) (Box 7)
  - Black Images (Toronto) (Box 7)
  - Black Knight Anarchist Group-London (Box 7)
  - Black Liberator, The (Chicago) (Box 7)
  - Black Liberator, The (Cuyahoga Community College) (Box 7)
  - Black Liberation Front of Canada (Box 7)
  - Black Lung Bulletin (Virginia) (Box 7)
  - Black News (New York) (Box 7)
  - Black/Out (Philadelphia, Detroit, New York) (Box 7)
  - Black Panther (Oakland, CA) (Box 7)
  - Black Poetry Journal (San Francisco) (Box 7)
  - Black Politics (Berkeley) (Box 7)
  - Black Power (San Francisco) (Box 7)
  - Black Rap, The (Urbana, IL) (Box 7)
  - Black Rose (Somerville, MA) (Box 7)
  - Black, Sally W. (Trenton State College) (Box 7)
  - Black Scholar, The (San Francisco) (Box 7)
  - Black Sports (New York) (Box 7)
  - Black Star (San Francisco) (Box 8)
  - Black Star (Tucson, AZ) (Box 8)
  - Black Sun Books (Box 8)
  - Black Theatre (New York) (Box 8)
  - Black Times (Albany, CA) (Box 8)
  - Black Vanguard (Danville, IL) (Box 8)
  - Black Voice (Montreal) (Box 8)
  - Black Voice, The (United Black Workers- Newark, NJ) (Box 8)
  - Black Workers Congress (Detroit, MI) (Box 8)
  - Black World, The (Pacoima, CA) (Box 8)
  - Blacklight (Washington DC) (Box 8)
  - Blackman, Selma (reference: Rosika Schwimmer) (Box 8)
  - Blackside, Inc. (Box 8)
  - Blade, The (Washington DC) (Box 8)
  - Blatt, Martin (reference: Ezra Heywood (Box 8)
  - Bluestein, Abe (reference: Hippolyte Havel) (Box 8)
  - Blum, Antoinette (reference: Les Socialistes Allemands contre la Guerre et le Militariisme) (Box 8)
  - Blumberg, Leonard (reference: Ben Reitman, Albert Parsons) (Box 8)
  - Bockman, Philip (re: “Stonewall 25”) (Box 8)
  - Body Politic (Toronto) (Box 8)
  - Boeck, George (Box 8)
  - Bogen, Nancy (reference: Hippolyte Havel) (Box 8)
  - Bograd, Mark (reference: use of IWW images for American Landscapes) (Box 8)
  - Bolduc, Lucie (Inc.) (Box 8)
  - Boletin A.I.T. (Caracas, Venezuala) (Box 8)
  - Boletin de Informacion Libertaria (Miami) (Box 8)
  - Bonanno, Alfredo (Box 8)
  - Bond, The (New York) (Box 8)
  - Bookchin, Murray (Box 8)
  - Booklegger Press (Box 8)
  - Books (Book dealer – England) (Box 8)
  - Boonin, Harry D. (reference: Voltairine de Cleyre, Broadstreet Riot) (Box 8)
  - Boos, Florence (reference: Max Nettlau, Victor Dave) (Box 8)
  - Boris, Eileen (reference: John Ruskin, William Morris) (Box 8)
  - Borle, Caroline (reference: images for Homestead Strike documentary, The River Ran Red) (Box 8)